Evolution is one of the greatest achievements in the scientific enquiry
Together with quantum mechanics and general relativity it is a pilar of the contemporary science
despite having simple concepts and dynamics it took centuries for its
comprehension
but even today that is still misunderstood by members of our society, especially
Between religious groups and pretentious sophists with iconiclast attitudes
These groups attacks the theory without understanding the meaning that the word theory has in the scientific community
Which is: an abstract framework that we fail, without
ambiguities, to make a distinction between it and the reality
despite this
distinguishability being a possibility produced by the abstraction itself
We may talk more about the structure of the scientific method and its
Terminologies in other videos now, we will focus in one of the fundamental concepts in the theory of evolution
its genetic variation and
thanks to it we observed the
Biodiversity that is out there
some may ask
If Evolution is True, how come we don't see frogs becoming snakes ? or
Why don;t we find fossils of a half man half monkey
First, we aren't living in a fantasy video game. Where a fish just
Flashes a bright light and becomes instantly in the dragon
Gee variation is a complex process that requires chemical reactions and it is a slow one
imagine that you've built a great beautiful mosaic
You are so amazed with your own work that you go to contemplate it every day
But without your knowledge a trickster has been visiting that as well
Every day it goes there and changes as a small piece of your beautiful mosaic
In the next day when you visit it, it's hard to notice it
Probably you would
Since a variation it's so small. You aren't able to distinguish what you see now from what you saw in the previous day
To do so you would require a more precise measurement
Methodology and just looking at it, but let's say now that you're hired to look at it and you want to know other places
You take a long trip and a year later you return while you were away
The trickster continued to visit your mosaic and applied its tricks on it
Excited to admire your work again. You rush to it and a frustration takes place in to your heart
You simply can't recognize it
The exclamation this is not my work echoes
But we know what took place
We know that it's been under a process that made it loose
information that violet in fact a process like this has been happening since the beginning of this little
That you notice the picture displayed in this video is like a mosaic since it is composed by qixels
Your one pixel is changing per frame
but I
Accelerated the process a little bit because it would take at least one hour to complete the process
as with our mosaic the variation is not relevant in the
distinguishability from one frame for the next one
Little only become relevant after some time when many pixels and suffer variation
And you may say that isn't another picture even if you can still observe
Similarities between the first picture and the last one with an evolution. It is the same
from
generation to generation a variation in our people happens
Slowly we are coming apart from our ancestors
These variations may occur due to mutations caused by radiation
Viruses chemical substances in the environment and in our food or simply spontaneous. Mist coating of the
Also our teams had the ability to be activated or deactivated
Genetics is we call this venom our habits because this
This kind of variation in the genome is not one that alters feels content but its expressiveness
Which will cause a slightly different sin despond development
chimpanzees on both her mutants and verbalist
Current our ancestors knew our customs
different variations happened in the theme among our ancestors
causing the emergence of different branches at culminated in our species and
contemporary rates a
simple step in this little
Represents a great leap in the process of the evolution
As you were able to detect that
Slowness and complexity are the reason why a mother won't look her baby as it was the monster